shopit.com 2008-06-16

# Shop, Buy, Build a Store & Sell – Shopit

  |  |    
---  
   
|  | 

| 

**Effective Date: December 20, 2006 **

Shopit, Inc. ("Shopit.com") values the users of our website (the "Website") and has created this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") to demonstrate our commitment to customer privacy. Your privacy and trust are very important to us. We recognize that you may be concerned about our collection, use and disclosure of the personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") that we collect when you use the Website and the services offered on the Website ("Shopit.com Services"). The terms "user", "seller", "profile", "user profile", "account" and "store" can all be used when referring to your Personal Information and where it may be used within this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy describes the information that we collect from you when you use the Website, how we collect this information, and what we do with it after we collect it. By using the Website you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com).  
  
---  
  
  * Does Shopit.com Ever Make Changes to its Privacy Policy?
  * What Types of Information Does Shopit.com Collect From Me?
  * How Does Shopit.com Use My Information?
  * When Will Shopit.com Disclose My Information to Third Parties?
  * What About Cookies and Web Beacons?
  * Listings, Public Profiles, Chat Rooms, Message Boards and Other Public Forums
  * How Can I Review and Make Changes to My Personal Information?
  * Tell-A-Friend
  * Security
  * Does This Privacy Policy Apply When I Access Third Party Websites?
  * What About Children's Privacy?
  * Can I Opt Out From Receiving Communications From Shopit.com?
  * Additional Information

Does Shopit.com Ever Make Changes to its Privacy Policy?

We may make changes to the Privacy Policy from time to time as they are warranted, so please review it frequently. We will notify you of any changes here, by email, by means of a notice on the Website, or by other reasonable means. If we make changes to our Privacy Policy, you should review the new Privacy Policy carefully to make sure you understand our practices and procedures. If you have any questions regarding the changes, please contact [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com).

Top  
  
What Types of Information Does Shopit.com Collect From Me?   
_Personal Information_ :  
Shopit.com provides Web-based service permitting users, among other things, to list, browse, buy, sell and trade products, and to communicate with other users via email, instant messages and chat. In almost all cases, we do not obtain any Personal Information about you unless you choose to reveal it. You are not required to disclose any personally identifiable information to us, although certain parts of the Website and certain services may not be available to you unless you do so.

We collect Personal Information, such as your name, address, phone number, email address, credit card number, and financial information that you submit to us in the user account registration process. You will also have the option to fill out an online profile with additional Personal Information about yourself. You may update your Personal Information at any time by logging into the Website and editing your online profile. You can view your updated profile to confirm your edits have been made.

Shopit.com also collects the information you submit or upload to your account to list items in your "store" or "widget" - the areas of your account where you advertise products you want to make available for sale to other users. Such information includes products descriptions, images, pricing and video commercials. As further provided in the Shopit.com Terms of Use, we are the sole owner of all information we collect relating to item listings. 

When you use Website email, chat, instant messaging or other similar features of the Website to communicate with other users, we collect the content of those communications. We will also collect the content of any messages you send to us, including emails sent in response to Shopit.com surveys or announcements regarding special offers, promotions or sweepstakes. If you sign up to receive a newsletter, we will collect your email address.

_Non-Personal Information_ :  
Like the operators of most websites, we also collect and log non-personal information that your browser makes available whenever you visit the Website, such as your browser type, browser language, the URL of the previous website you visited, Internet domain and host names, your ISP, operating system, clickstream patterns, your Internet protocol (IP) Address, and the dates and times that the Website and the Shopit.com services are accessed ("Non-Personal Information"). We also track and compile aggregate statistics regarding use of the Website ("Aggregate Data"). In addition, we contract with several online partners who may track Non-Personal Information and Aggregate Data to help us manage, monitor and optimize our Website and the Shopit.com services and to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising, communications and visitor use of the Website. To do this, we may use web beacons and cookies. See "What About Cookies and Web Beacons?" below. 

Non-Personal Information and Aggregate Data cannot be easily used to identify you personally. Although new techniques exist to obtain personally identifiable information using IP addresses, Shopit.com does not use IP addresses for that purpose; provided, however, that we may log the IP address of a user's computer and compare the online information provided in the Shopit.com profile to try to prevent, eliminate, and investigate user fraud.

Top  
  
How Does Shopit.com Use My Information?  
_Personal Information_ :  
We use Personal Information primarily for our own internal purposes, such as providing, maintaining, evaluating, and improving the Shopit.com services and the Website, and providing customer support. If you create a Shopit.com account, we will use the information that you provide us to communicate with you regarding "store" sales or trade transactions, to provide you with periodic updates and notices regarding the Shopit.com services, and to provide you with promotional information regarding our company or partners . Similarly, if you sign up to receive a Shopit.com newsletter, we will use the email address you provide to send you the newsletters.

We use all information you submit relating to items for sale in your "store" to create listings for such items. We also transmit offers, counteroffers and similar user communications in the course of facilitating purchase, sale and trade transactions between users.

Shopit.com automatically displays a limited amount of personally identifiable user profile information, including users' pictures (if provided), age and location to other users and the public in order to facilitate interaction and foster a sense of community among users of the Shopit.com services. We encourage users not to reveal additional Personal Information on the public profile, such as addresses and telephone numbers, but users may provide any Personal Information they wish in private messages to other users. Users' email addresses are not available in the public profile; however, a user's Shopit.com email address is revealed to another user if the user sends a message to the other user through the service. The recipient's Shopit.com email address is not available to the sender unless the recipient chooses to reply. Users' non-Shopit.com email addresses are not displayed or revealed to other users when they communicate through the service. To facilitate searching and finding friends and acquaintances on the service, Shopit.com allows users to search for other members based on Personal Information provided in numerous categories in the public profiles.

We may periodically view or access individual records for the purpose of resolving a problem or dispute, a support issue, a suspected violation of the Shopit Terms of Service or as may be required by law. Shopit.com uses age information to limit access to Shopit.com services to users 13 and older. For more information, see "What About Children's Privacy?" below and the section relating to children in the Shopit.com Terms of Service.

_Non-Personal Information_ :  
We use Non-Personal Information and Aggregate Data to track the use of the Website and the Shopit.com Services and for other internal purposes, such as improving Website security, diagnosing and resolving technical problems, providing, maintaining, evaluating, and improving Shopit.com services and the Website, and monitoring, preventing and investigating user fraud and abuse. This information helps us constantly improve the quality of the Website and the Shopit.com service.

Top  
  
When Will Shopit.com Disclose My Information to Third Parties?   
Except as expressly stated in this Privacy Policy, in the Shopit.com Terms of Service, or at the time we request information, we do not disclose customer email addresses or any other Personal Information to any third parties.   
_Disclosure to Successors_ :  
We may disclose your Personal Information to any successor-in-interest of ours, such as a company that acquires us. In the event Shopit.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger or acquisition by or with another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Personal Information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or by a notice on our Website of any such change in ownership or control of your Personal Information. You may not be able to receive notices from us if your browser is not set to accept cookies.

_Disclosure to Unaffiliated Third Parties_ :  
We may disclose your Personal Information to prevent an emergency; to prevent harm to others; to respond to legal requirements; to investigate or prevent illegal activities, suspected infringement or fraud, or violations of the Shopit.com Terms of Service; to protect or enforce our rights and policies; to protect or enforce the rights of a third party; or as required or permitted by law (including, without limitation, to comply with a subpoena, search warrant or court order).

_Disclosure to Third-Party Service Providers_ :  
We may contract with various third parties who help us provide, maintain and improve the Website and the Shopit.com Services. We may subcontract out production, fulfillment, analytics, reporting or other operations. We also contract with several service providers to help manage, monitor and optimize our Website and the Shopit.com Services and to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising, communications and how visitors use the Website. In the course of providing services to Shopit.com, these third parties may come into contact with your Personal Information. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent such third parties from copying, storing, retaining, using or disclosing your Personal Information for any purpose other than providing the services in question.

_Disclosure to Third-Party Advertisers and Marketers_ :

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. Shopit.com does not provide any Personal Information to the advertiser when you interact with or view a targeted ad. Please note that this Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies and Personal Information by Shopit.com and does not cover the use of cookies and Personal Information by any third-party advertisers. Be aware that Shopit.com is not responsible for the privacy practices of our advertising partners. We encourage you to use prudence and caution in clicking through to websites for advertised products and services. We also urge you to review carefully the advertising privacy policies of our advertising partners, to the extent they are accessible.

Our Web advertising partners may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to Shopit.com and other websites, where you saw certain advertisements and which ads you clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements on this Website and other sites about goods and services that our advertising partners believe will be of most interest to you. Shopit.com does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third-party ad servers or ad networks. Advertisers do not have access to Shopit.com's cookies. See also "What About Cookies and Web Beacons?" below.

In the course of providing online advertising services to websites and advertisers, certain of our advertising partners also use web beacons permitting them to analyze advertising campaigns and the general usage patterns of visitors to websites. In all such instances, anonymous information about your visit to a particular website is sent to ad servers for processing. Advertising partners may also use web beacons to deliver targeted advertising to your browser. See also "What About Cookies and Web Beacons?" below.

Shopit.com has established strategic relationships with certain trusted third-party marketers and advertisers who may wish to send you occasional e-mails regarding services or products that you may find of interest or for other reasons that are disclosed to us and that we believe to be appropriate and consistent with our commitment to prevent abuse of your Personal Information. Unless you opt out of receiving these messages (see "Can I Opt Out�?" below), Shopit.com may provide your Shopit.com email addresses to these trusted marketers and advertisers and permit them to send targeted marketing and advertisement communications to you. We may also provide to these third parties certain user profile information together with user's Shopit.com email addresses to permit them to target communications to users with specific interests or other demographics. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent such third parties from copying, storing, retaining, using or disclosing your Personal Information for any purpose other than providing the services described. We encourage you to use prudence and caution in responding to emails from third parties. Moreover, any transactions you conduct with a third party will be subject to that party's privacy policy, which we urge you to review carefully. Email messages from marketing and advertising partners may contain web beacons allowing such parties to track your receipt of such messages. See also "What About Cookies and Web Beacons?" below.

_Disclosure to Sellers_ :  
If you acquire a product on Shopit.com, Shopit.com may provide your name, and the city and state information provided by you to the seller. In the Seller Agreement, Shopit.com contractually obligates each seller not to use or disclose this information for any purposes other than internal record keeping, and for marketing their shops if you have opted in to receive marketing material directly from the seller. We cannot guarantee all sellers will comply with this obligation. If you believe a Shopit.com seller is using your Personal Information in a way that does not comply with our rules, please contact [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com) and include your user name, the seller's user name and a description of your concerns.

_Disclosure of Non-Personal Information_ :  
We will disclose Aggregate Data and Non-Personal Information in aggregate form to strategic partners, advertisers, investors, consultants, advisors, and others. You may not opt out of the sharing of this information. However, it cannot be easily used to identify you personally.

Top  
  
What About Cookies and Web Beacons?   
A cookie is a small file placed on the hard drive of your computer. Most websites use cookies. We use cookies to track your use of the Website and the Shopit.com services, provide you with a more personalized user experience, and to allow you to login and begin use of the Shopit.com services automatically when you visit the Website. Users who disable their web browsers' ability to accept cookies will be able to browse the Website but will not be able to use certain services and features.

A web beacon (also known as a clear GIF or pixel tag) is an often-transparent graphic image, usually no larger than a 1x1 pixel that is placed on a web page or in an e-mail that is used to monitor the behavior of the user visiting the Website or receiving the e-mail. In all such instances, the web beacon collects only anonymous information about your visit to a particular website or receipt of email and sends that information to servers for processing. Shopit.com and/or its third-party service providers use pixel tags to better understand the traffic patterns of visitors. 

Cookies and web beacons used by Shopit.com and our online partners are not linked to Personal Information. Some of our users may use cookies or web beacons on our Website in connection with their stores. We have no access to or control over these cookies and web beacons. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies and web beacons by Shopit.com and our service providers only and does not cover the use of cookies or web beacons by any other third party, Shopit.com user, advertiser or marketer. For more information about how our third party advertising and marketing partners use cookies and web beacons, see "Disclosure to Third-Party Advertisers and Marketers" above.

Top  
  
Listings, Public Profiles, Chat Rooms, Message Boards and Other Public Forums    
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily store, post, or transmit Personal Information on or through public areas of the Website, such as in public user profiles, message board postings, chat discussions, item descriptions, listing images or videos, that information may be accessed, collected and used by other users, including people that you do not know. Among other things, other users may use such information to send you unsolicited communications. We are not responsible for the actions of others. Therefore, you should use care in transmitting information on the Website and only disclose your Personal Information to other users that you know to be trustworthy. You should not assume that your content will be kept private.

Top  
  
How Can I Review and Make Changes to My Personal Information?   
You may modify your Personal Information or deactivate your account at any time by logging into your account, accessing your profile and changing the information stored there. In some cases, you may also specify how Shopit.com, other users and/or third parties communicate with you. See also "Can I Opt Out�?" below. You can also obtain a copy of, and request that we correct errors in, your Personal Information by emailing us at [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com). For your protection, you will be required to provide proof of your identity to obtain a copy of your Personal Information. If you would like to deactivate or terminate your account you can also contact Shopit.com customer service by clicking here or by sending an email to [support@shopit.com](mailto:support@shopit.com).

Top  
  
Tell-A-Friend  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about the Website, the Shopit.com services or an item listed in your store, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend one or more emails inviting or reminding him or her to visit the Website or your store. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending such emails and tracking the success of our referral program.

Top  
  
Security   
The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We use commercially reasonable security measures to protect user information stored within our database from loss, misuse, theft of alteration, both during transmission and once we receive it. Shopit.com hosts the Website and the Shopit.com service in a secure server environment that uses a firewall and other advanced technology to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. When you enter sensitive information such as a credit card number and/or social security number on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We restrict access to user information to those employees and subcontractors who need access to perform their job functions, such as our customer service personnel, technical staff and third-party service providers. Moreover, Shopit.com user accounts are secured by user-created passwords to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure appropriate use of user information.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Of course, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of your username and password. For any additional information about the security measures we use on Shopit.com, please contact us at [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com). Please note that, as further described above, Shopit.com provides several third-party service providers, advertisers and marketers with access to various types of user Personal Information solely for the purpose of permitting such parties to furnish services to users or the Website. To our knowledge, such parties employ reasonable security measures to protect user information against unauthorized access or use. We cannot monitor or control handling of user information by these parties, however, and their use of such information is accordingly governed by the privacy policies and terms of service of those parties.

Top  
  
Does This Privacy Policy Apply When I Access Third Party Websites?   
You may be able to access third party websites or services directly from the Website. This Privacy Policy does not apply when you access third party websites or linked services. We cannot control how third parties may use Personal Information you disclose to them, so you should carefully review the privacy policy of any third party website you visit before using it or disclosing your Personal Information to its provider. 

Top  
  
What About Children's Privacy?   
Protecting the privacy of children is VERY important to us. For that reason, the Website is not directed to children under the age of 13 and we do not structure any part of our subscriber or affiliate services to attract anyone under that age. If parents believe their child (any age under 18) has accessed our service without their permission, Shopit.com encourages them to install parental control software on their computers permitting them to block their child's access our Website. For more information on Shopit.com's policies and procedures regarding children, please see the section entitled "Children" in the Shopit.com Terms of Service. You may also visit http://www.ftc.gov/kidzprivacy for information from the Federal Trade Commission about protecting children's privacy online.

_Under Thirteen_  
The Shopit.com Services are intended for users ages 13 and older only, and our system does not allow anyone who indicates they are under the age of 13 to register as a user. We will not knowingly collect or use any Personal Information from children that we know to be under the age of 13. In addition, we will delete any information in our database that we know originates from a child under the age of 13. Although advertisements promoting Shopit.com on third-party websites may unintentionally reach children under 13, Swapwedo.com does not target advertising to children in that age range.

_Thirteen to Seventeen_  
Prospective users between the ages of 13 and 17 can only use the Shopit.com Services subject to their parents or legal guardian's supervision and consent, as further described in the policies and procedures outlined in the section of the Shopit.com Terms of Service entitled "Children". If you are between the ages of 13 and 17, you, your parent, or your legal guardian may request that we modify, remove or deactivate any of your Personal Information in our database and/or opt out from receiving communications from us. If you wish to do so, please see "How Can I Review and Make Changes to My Personal Information?" above and "Can I Opt Out�?" below, or contact us at [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com). Shopit.com may insert a prominent notice of your age on your profile or store, if you are under 18, to notify other users of your age. Alternatively, if you are under 18 and you enter into a sale or trade transaction with another user, we may generate and send an automated email or other similar communication to the other user notifying him or her of your age.

Top  
  
Can I Opt Out From Receiving Communications From Shopit.com?   
When users register on the Website, we provide them with the opportunity to �opt out' of having their Personal Information used for certain purposes. If, after registering, you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and/or other promotional communications, you may opt out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication, by emailing us at [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com), or by modifying Privacy Settings in your account profile on the Website. We reserve the right to decline requests to opt out of important service notices regarding the Shopit.com service or the company. 

If we disclose your Personal Information to a third party in a manner that is not set forth in this Privacy Policy, you will be notified so that you can make an informed choice about sharing your Personal Information with that third party.

Top  
  
Additional Information    
Should you have any additional questions, concerns or comments regarding your privacy and the Shopit.com Privacy Policy, please contact [privacy@shopit.com](mailto:privacy@shopit.com) or write to:

Shopit.com, Inc.  
11726 San Vicente Blvd.  
Suite 420  
Los Angeles, CA 90049

Top
